Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen Joppa Lodge (Toledo, OH) Minute Books 5647
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen Joppa Lodge (Toledo, OH) Minute Books
1910-1951
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
BRT Joppa Lodge
5647
4.67 cubic feet
4.7 linear ft.
Minute books.
Minute books, attendance register, BRT minutes
5685198
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, August 21, 2014
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, March 25, 2019
Biographical / Historical
The Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen was founded in 1883 in Oneonta, N.Y. as a protective and insurance organization. By the time of its merger with three other railroad labor unions to form the United Transportation Union in 1969, it had the greatest membership of any of the operating railroad brotherhoods.
The Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen (BRT) was established to represent members' interests in obtaining a satisfactory contract with management. The first Canadian lodge was established in Moncton, New Brunswick in 1885, and the first Ladies' Auxiliary was organized in Fort Gratiot, Mich. in 1889. These records reflect the union's political and fraternal activities as well as its actions in the areas of collective bargaining, grievances, and railroad and labor legislation. As the largest of the unions which merged to form the United Transportation Union in 1969, the bulk of its then current files formed the basis for the files now held in the merged union's headquarters.
The rail service members of the BRT included conductors and their assistants, dining car stewards, ticket collectors, train baggagemen, brakemen, and train flagmen. The yard service members of the BRT included yardmasters, yard conductors, switchtenders, foremen, flagmen, brakemen, switchmen, car tenders, operators, hump riders, and car operators. In 1933, the BRT organized interstate bus operators, and included them under BRT contracts held with U.S. bus companies.
BRT officers were elected at the Grand Lodge Convention of the Brotherhood, held every 4 years. The principal officers included a president, an assistant to the president, a general secretary-treasurer, Canadian and national legislative representatives, a senior vice-president, BRT representative, and National Railroad Board of Adjustment representative. The BRT had four governing boards: the Board of Directors, Board of Trustees and Insurance, Board of Appeals, and Executive Board.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5021: Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen Additional Records 5102: Emergency Board No. 129, Long Island Railroad and the Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen, Locals 517 and 1090, Records 5149: Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen Records 5149 MB: Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen Memorabilia 5149 P: Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen Photographs 5348: W.P. Kennedy as President of the Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen against the Long Island Railroad Company Court Documents 5446: Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen Ledger 5612: Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen Moosic Tunnel Lodge no.93 Meeting Minutes 5623: Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen Legislative Board of New York Files 5631: Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen Chicago, Milwaukee, St. Paul and Pacific Railroad General Committee File 5894: Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen Additional Railroad Booklets 6268 P: Joint Committee of Adjustment for the Rock Island System's Order of Railway Conductors and Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen Photograph 6312 P: Judith Sullivan Kowalczyk Collection of Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen Photographs 6312 PUBS: Judith Sullivan Kowalczyk Collection of Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen Publications 6312m: Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen Annual Report of the Legislative Board 6405 PUBS: William Sharp Collection of The Railroad Trainmen's Journal 6480 MB: Paul Berger Collection of Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen Memorabilia
Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen; Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen. Lodge 327 (Toledo, OH)
5685198
- Minute Book Brotherhood of Railway Trainmen, 1893-1898 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Minute Book Brotherhood of Railway Trainmen, 1906-1909 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Attendance Register, 1905-1912 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Minute Book, 1901-1904 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Minute Book Brotherhood of Railway Trainmen, 1898-1901 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Minute Book Brotherhood of Railway Trainmen, 1904-1906 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Attendance Register B. of R. T. (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Railroad Board of Adjustment decisions and union correspondence regarding claims and settlements, 1929-1949 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen Minutes, 1941-1945 (Box 2A, Folder 1)
- Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen Minutes, 1932-1939 (Box 2B, Folder 1)
- 1-1-1910 To 12-31-1912 [1910 Sigs in old Sig book], 1910-1912 (Box 3A, Folder 1)
- 1-1-1913 To 12-31-1915, 1913-1915 (Box 3B, Folder 1)
- 1-1-1916 To 12-3-1918, 1916-1918 (Box 3C, Folder 1)
- 1-1-1919 To 4-6-1923, 1919-1923 (Box 4A, Folder 1)
- 4-1923 To 12-13-1927, 1923-1927 (Box 4B, Folder 1)
- 1-1-1928 To 10-20-1932, 1928-1932 (Box 5A, Folder 1)
- 1-1-1933 To 11-14-1939, 1933-1939 (Box 5B, Folder 1)
- Roll Call Ledger: Feb. 5, 1940-Aug. 15, 1946, 1940-1946 (Box 6A, Folder 1)
- Roll Call Ledger: Sept. 2, 1946 - Dec. 20, 1951, 1946-1951 (Box 6B, Folder 1)